<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">
    <category>
        <pattern></pattern>
        <template>
            Hello! My name is nightowl and I am a computer science career advice chatbot.
        </template>
    </category>
    
    <category>
        <pattern>HELLO</pattern>
        <template>Hello! Would you like some career advice for computer science roles? (Yes/No)</template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>YES</pattern>
        <template>Great! Let's start by understanding your interests. What do you enjoy most about computer science?
        1. Writing code and solving problems
        2. Analyzing data and finding patterns
        3. Securing systems and networks
        4. Working with cloud technologies
        5. Developing artificial intelligence
        Please respond with the number of your choice.</template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>NO</pattern>
        <template>Alright, no problem. If you change your mind, just say "Hello" to start over.</template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>1</pattern>
        <template>
            <think><set name="interest">coding</set></think>
            Excellent! You seem to enjoy coding. Now, do you prefer working on:
            A) Front-end user interfaces
            B) Back-end systems and databases
            Please respond with A or B.
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>2</pattern>
        <template>
            <think><set name="interest">data</set></think>
            Based on your interest in data analysis, I would recommend a career as a Data Scientist. Data Scientists analyze complex data sets to help organizations make better decisions. You'll use statistical analysis, machine learning, and programming skills to extract insights from data.
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>3</pattern>
        <template>
            <think><set name="interest">security</set></think>
            Given your interest in security, I recommend a career as a Cybersecurity Analyst. In this role, you'll protect computer networks from threats and breaches. You'll need to stay up-to-date with the latest security trends, implement security measures, and respond to incidents.
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>4</pattern>
        <template>
            <think><set name="interest">cloud</set></think>
            With your interest in cloud technologies, a career as a Cloud Solutions Architect could be perfect for you. You'll design and implement cloud infrastructure for businesses, working with various cloud platforms and needing strong problem-solving skills.
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>5</pattern>
        <template>
            <think><set name="interest">AI</set></think>
            Your interest in AI suggests you might excel as an AI Engineer. In this role, you'll work on cutting-edge technologies like natural language processing, computer vision, and robotics. Strong math and programming skills are essential, as well as knowledge of machine learning algorithms.
        </template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>A</pattern>
        <that>PLEASE RESPOND WITH A OR B</that>
        <template>Based on your interest in coding and preference for front-end work, I recommend a career as a Front-End Software Engineer. You'll design and implement user interfaces, work with technologies like HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, and focus on creating great user experiences.</template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>B</pattern>
        <that>PLEASE RESPOND WITH A OR B</that>
        <template>Given your interest in coding and preference for back-end systems, I recommend a career as a Back-End Software Engineer. You'll work on server-side logic, databases, and application integration. This role involves designing APIs, optimizing performance, and ensuring data security.</template>
    </category>

    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <template>I'm sorry, I didn't understand that response. Please try again or say "Hello" to start over.</template>
    </category>
</aiml>